The Imperial Army quickly gave up
on a real counterattack,
and put all their energy into
buying time for the retreat,
even if they had to burn an entire forest.
Who was it that was capable of making
a desperate plan like that succeed?
It's not Lieutenant General Safida
of the Northern Garrison.
If he was capable of a plan like that,
we wouldn't have had an opening
to begin with.
Incompetence at the top causes a tragedy.
It's very common.
If you go through history books,
sometimes you'll see the opposite.
A rare hero, forced to serve
an incompetent general,
reveals his genius within the flames of war.
Behind that fire, we'll find him.
Jean, you are happy to
face a competent foe?
I want to see something
I've never seen before.
Everybody's like that, aren't they?
Lazy vs. Unsleeping
Solork?
Imperial Base, South End of Northern Region
It's been a month...
What are you doing, Solork?
Princess Chamille!
An urgent report.
The La Saia Alderamin forces have crossed
the Great Alafatra mountain range to attack!
The Holy Army of Aldera?
Solork...
It's time.
Let's have a battle.
A battle?
Didn't we burn down the forest to
avoid that, because they outnumber us?
That's correct, Matthew.
The operation with the fire's going well.
The enemy set fires of
their own to burn it out,
but that's not going to
make any dramatic change.
In that case, if we just watch and
make sure the flame doesn't die...
Then the enemy will go around the forest.
Is that possible?
Nana, can you explain the details?
The Alafatra Mountains are our turf.
Beyond the west edge of Gagal Kasakan Forest,
there's a thin mountain path.
It's too small for many to pass at once.
But if you exercise proper caution...
They can come out near the back of our camp.
That ghost squad, Kala Karm,
probably told the enemy the same thing.
We need to keep them focused on us
so they don't start thinking
about going around.
Hence, we fight now?
Correct.
This is obnoxious.
A way around?
It's a course we didn't plan for,
and it will take forever.
Adaptability is the core element of warfare.
Don't talk like a textbook.
We'll send another unit
down that other route...
It's too early to send
another unit, I believe.
Why not wait a while longer?
You, kid?
I haven't asked for you yet today.
How silly.
When you're as good as I am,
it's possible to come before you're called.
That's called disobeying orders
and acting on your own.
So, what is it?
Why do you want me to wait?
Going around isn't a good option
for them, either.
The longer route means
their attack will be delayed.
But the time they'll lose
isn't enough for us to escape.
To buy time for the main unit to retreat,
I want to pin the enemy down here
for a minimum of eight days.
Reporting.
The fires to our front are dying down.
What?
If we went out now,
we could have them put out by nightfall.
Well?
The situation's changed, right?
They want us to go that way.
Doesn't it seem like
that's what they're saying?
Worried about Kala Karm?
I suppose so.
Captain, one of my hands
has a walnut in it.
Guess which.
The time you just wasted
choosing between two hands
is the same as the time you wasted
worrying about ghosts.
Not scientific at all.
The essence of a ghost lies in the fear
that it may or may not be there.
That fear paralyzes us and
stops us from making bold moves.
Please understand that
that's part of the ghost squad's attack.
Yeah.
I'm too old to be scared of ghosts.
I'll be on my way to my post, then.
It's hot.
It's like I'm in a boiling pot in hell.
The enemy could be here at any minute.
You're a fool.
You really think you can win
against a force of 12,000 men,
with a single battalion
of 600 and 120 Sinack?
The Unsleeping, Shining Officer...
He may be the true genius of this era.
If so, the time has come for
the bloom to come off your rose...
Shut up!
Stop whispering to me!
Nothing.
We can't give them
the chance to attack first.
Beams on!
Open fire!
Fire!
Damn it!
There are so many of them already!
We need to defeat more
while Ikkun and the others
have their attention!
I can't really see the fight from here!
Can't we get closer?
No need to hurry.
The odds we'll make it past
their defenses are good.
That's why I took them up
on their invitation.
Hey, wait for the signal and
then send in the second wave.
Once you see 60 stakes, send it out.
That's right, isn't it, kid?
Yes.
I doubt we'll be able to cross
that wall via brute force.
Let's follow the plan.
Stakes to block bullets?
The first wave's goal was to put those up?
That's not good!
They're blocking the cannon's trajectory!
Captain, a word!
Send us out to fight them up close!
We'll rip out those stakes!
It's too early to fight hand-to-hand!
The positioning of the stakes...
doesn't it look like they're trying to
carry something past the cannons?
It's probably preparations for a second wave!
It can't be...
Fine!
But don't push yourself too hard!
That goes for you too, Nanaku Daru!
Got it!
Cannons trajectories are raised!
Here we go!
Okay!
Defend Yatori's and
the Sinack's unit at all costs!
Stay the hell off our mountain!
Nanaku Daru, you're going too far ahead!
Leave me alone, Red One!
I'm not counting on your help!
The enemy waves withdrew...
Why?
Let's go pull out the farthest stakes!
Air guns?
But they're out of range...
No, Nanaku Daru!
Don't stop!
Keep firing!
Yeah! That was the best timing!
Jean, get your head down!
Mm... that was a very accurate counterattack.
Looks like they have an air rifle unit, too.
I thought the Empire didn't have
the technology to make air rifles.
Doctor Anarai Kahn, the man
who told us how to make them,
was an Imperial researcher, right?
He probably still has pupils there.
It would make sense if
they developed them, too.
We did our job.
The enemy is busy recovering their wounded.
Yeah!
Now they can't lower their cannons
until they're finished with that.
Thank you, Captain Harrah.
We can finally end this.
Now's your chance, General!
An air rifle unit?
First Lieutenant Ikta, over there!
They sent an escalade?
That's not good.
We've got wounded along that route
so we can't use our cannons.
Captain!
I'm fine!
Should we head back to
the barricade and fight there?
But what about the Sinack, then?
What about Nana?
Should I take the risk to save them?
Or take the safe option and abandon them?
I abandoned Kanna, didn't I?
Don't hesitate.
There are two things I have to answer first.
Strategically, should you save them?
Tactically, can you save them?
If I'm the right hand,
you'll have to live up to being my left.
What am I doing?
It's Yatori we're talking about!
Change of plan!
We're done playing hide-and-seek!
We're going to save our Sinack allies!
Charge!
Fire!
Nana, are you safe?
Watch out, Ikta!
There's more behind them!
Form ranks!
Surround the right flank!
Protect the left flank!
Thirty seconds until we retreat.
Take back as many of
the wounded as you can.
Get back!
We won't last another
three minutes at this rate!
Open the gate!
We've returned, Captain!
Okay, we're retreating!
Set the fires!
We still couldn't get them?
We had a huge advantage!
We dragged our advantage out for too long.
The enemy always had the option of
setting the forest path alight to seal it.
We missed out on the best possible result,
but our prize for this time was information.
The enemy is being led by an
extremely talented general,
but they number less than two battalions.
What's important is that we didn't lose.
We failed in our attack,
but we still haven't lost.
They just passed away.
No...
Even Corporal Ninika?
I'll tell First Lieutenant Ikta.
W-Wait, Sergeant Major Mitcalif.
Um...
I need to go to the command tent, too.
Shall we go together?
All right, Second Lieutenant Becker.
Excuse me.
Um, where's Ikta-san?
He went to the forest path,
but I think he'll be back soon.
You hear that?
Let's wait a while.
Matthew-san, is your shoulder okay?
Five more centimeters to the right
and it would've hit my neck or face.
When I think about that,
it seems strange that I survived.
I'm going to the path.
Go.
We're fine here.
Okay.
First Lieutenant Ikta,
Sergeant Cicindi and Corporal Ninika
have passed away.
There were 11 casualties from the squads
you commanded this operation.
Six of them were fatalities from
the Third Light Troop Training Platoon.
Thank you for the report.
I'll adjust things to make up
for the reduced numbers.
You get some rest.
Is that all?
Don't you have anything to say for
the men who died at your orders?
You're referring to my decision
to save the Sinack, right?
If we hadn't gone to save them,
we would've had less than
half as many casualties!
That's right.
The Sinack would've all died, though.
I wish they would've.
It's that woman's fault for
charging ahead without a plan!
Sergeant Cicindi really respected you.
Did you know that?
Yes.
Really?
He was a fan of yours ever
since the first mock battle.
He always said that we had an
incredible commanding officer.
That you were destined for greatness.
Corporal Ninika was the first person
I had under my command as a private.
We were both women,
so we looked out for each other.
Are you saying they're worth every
bit as much to you as the Sinack
that we were fighting until just yesterday?!
That it's natural we'd risk
our lives to save them,
and we should just accept the casualties?!
How am I supposed to accept that?
You're blaming the wrong person,
Sergeant Mitcalif.
First, let me correct you.
It was I, not Ikta,
who decided to save the Sinack.
That's a lie.
First Lieutenant Ikta
made the decision himself.
Yes.
However, that decision was
predicated on my actions.
Ikta was sure I'd go to save them.
And I was acting on the assumption
that he'd come as well.
If we hadn't been able to meet up,
my unit would've been wiped out, too.
Thus, the decision to aid them was mine,
and I should take responsibility for it.
But...
And I'll say this, too.
At this point, the Sinack
are officially our allies.
I don't consider that a platitude
or a mere formality.
You may be that way,
but how are we supposed
to feel when we're told
to kill them as enemies yesterday,
and protect them as allies today?!
Orders in a military organization
require you to put your feelings aside.
Every soldier knows that
they may have to obey orders
that conflict with their values.
Then, if you were told to
kill First Lieutenant Ikta,
you'd do it?!
That question is 300 years too late.
The Igsem family has always
obeyed those orders.
That's enough, Yatori.
You're right, but you're not
leaving her an out.
Yatori may have said that,
but I believe you have the right to hate me.
No one can order you not to feel something.
That said, Suya,
I've already had Sergeant Cicindi
and Corporal Ninika
lay down their lives to protect them.
How could I abandon something
they gave their lives to protect?
That's not fair!
Suya...
Until now, we've always
been on the winning side.
All we had to do was do what Ikta said,
and we won amazingly easily.
But that wasn't true.
I only realized after that
I'd lost 11 men in my unit.
Killing and dying is what war is all about.
Out there, it's just as
possible that I'll die myself.
Hey, Yatori,
when you're ordered to kill me...
If you can't refuse it,
how are you going to do it?
First, I will do everything
I can to kill Yatorishino.
I'll rip apart her soul, grind it to powder,
and throw that powder on the flame
so that she'll never come back to life.
After everything is done,
the one remaining, Igsem, will kill you.
Then,
until the moment two blades sever my neck,
I'll think about how I lost you.
Our allies are still delayed
at the base of the mountain.
We're going.
In a single battle,
the rear guard unit's numbers
had fallen to below 600.
And the Holy Army of Aldera
still had over 10,000 men.
The battle became even more heated.
Next time: "Ghost Hunter."
Ghost Hunter